<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>History on rohanarni.com</title>
    <link>https://rohanarni.com/categories/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on rohanarni.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rohanarni.com/categories/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Hegelian Philosophy Can Help Us Understand Where The World Is Headed</title>
      <link>https://rohanarni.com/posts/hegel-modern-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rohanarni.com/posts/hegel-modern-day/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Those who cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it.&amp;rdquo; - George Santayana
The present can seem like a very unstable and turbulent time. It seems as if the world is splitting itself apart, becoming more polarized and opinionated. However, to understand the direction the world is headed, we need to look back in the past for answers.
Now, Hegel is notorious for being incredibly difficult to read. His works are often long-winded and use poor english to convey his thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Starry Night</title>
      <link>https://rohanarni.com/posts/starry-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 09:10:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rohanarni.com/posts/starry-night/</guid>
      <description>Since the dawn of human civilization, the night sky has captivated us in a way that no other object has. From the silvery moon rising in the sky to the tiny pinpricks of light we now know as stars and planets, humans have spent countless hours observing and documenting the night sky. The process began as far back as the Babylonians and their written record of the night sky, to the Mesoamerican civilizations who based a large majority of their calendar on the moon, and then the Indian and Arabic civilizations with their massive technological advancements to help observe the night sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marbury V. Madison: The First Supreme Court Case</title>
      <link>https://rohanarni.com/posts/marbury-v-madison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 04:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rohanarni.com/posts/marbury-v-madison/</guid>
      <description>On February 24, 1803, the first and most influential supreme court case of America occurred. This case lives in obscurity to most citizens, but without it, the Supreme Court would not have the power it has today. The issue of the case arose from a seemingly simple dispute. It all began during the Election of 1800. When incumbent president John Adams was voted out of office, he created a scheme to keep his party, the Federalists, in control of one of the branches of the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why China’s History Matters So Much</title>
      <link>https://rohanarni.com/posts/why-china-history-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 22:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rohanarni.com/posts/why-china-history-matters/</guid>
      <description>Hi. It’s been a while. Sorry for not writing at all! I’ve been pretty busy, but I didn’t write because I was very lazy. So anyways, I’m back! Let’s get into today’s topic!
China. You can’t read the news without hearing about China. China is predicted to take over the US as the number one global superpower by 2032, and some estimate that to be even earlier. But how did this happen?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
