<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>History on rohanarni.com</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on rohanarni.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 09:10:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Raytheon Radarange</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/technology-radarange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 09:10:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/technology-radarange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Raytheon Radarange was the first commercially available microwave. A clunky, chrome box weighing over 340 kg and costing over $5,000, the Radarange wasn’t widely adopted at the time. However, this artifact was chosen because it was a foundational step in advancing consumer food technology by changing the way Americans prepared food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Radarange was invented as a result of melted chocolate. In a Raytheon lab, Percy Spencer realized that his candy bar melted when he placed his chocolate bar next to a magnetron. Spencer realized that the magnetron (a special type of vacuum tube) was producing electromagnetic radiation, causing his chocolate bar to melt. Fascinated by this result, Spencer then took a bag of corn kernels and placed them near his magnetron, all of which popped into fresh, hot popcorn all over his lab. Presumably after a few laughs, Spencer and Raytheon realized the true potential of the technology they had on their hands and refined it to create the Radarange, sold starting in 1947.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altair 8800 Advertisement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/technology-altair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 09:10:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/technology-altair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/altair.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Altair 8800 Advertisement&#34; /&gt; &lt;/center&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This is an advertisement for the Altair 8800 personal computer in the Popular Electronics Magazine. The Altair 8800 was the first commercially successful personal computer kit and was sold beginning in January 1975, when it was featured on the cover of the Popular Electronics magazine. This magazine had been the life and soul of the personal electronics culture in America, and being nominated to the cover marketed the Altair 8800 massively. It was sold as a DIY kit for around $400, and it was a plain metal box with switches and blinking lights. It was nowhere close to the PCs that consumers have today, but it was a massive success with the “hackers” of the 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Existentialism and Counterculture Through American History</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/existentialism-ush/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 09:10:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/existentialism-ush/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the moment we are born, there are expectations placed on us: go to school, find a job, start a family, build a life. Society gives us a blueprint on how to live a “meaningful” life. However, existentialism fundamentally rejects the premise that we have some “predetermined” purpose; instead, it suggests that it is up to an individual to find purpose in their life. Existentialists become aware of the “absurdity” of human existence: the fact that life itself lacks any inherent meaning beyond what we choose to give it. This problem, where humans seek purpose in a universe that offers none, leads to a dilemma: should we accept the illusion of meaning from society, or should we create our own?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Social Contract in the Digital Age</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/social-contract-digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 09:10:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/social-contract-digital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen the rise of many great empires and nations–Romans and their expansive empire, the British and their global dominance–only to see it crumble to dust. We can blame a lot of things on these collapses: new rising nations, changing technology, unexpected external factors. However, the collapse typically comes from within, as the relationship between the government and its citizens starts to crack and fail. This dramatic decay can be explained by a concept called the social contract. The social contract is one of the most important ideas in political philosophy (the study of the nature of politics, society, and the relationship between citizens and government). It states that citizens willingly consent to give up some personal freedoms to a governing authority, in exchange for the protection of their rights. To put it really simply, citizens give up some free will to gain protection from the government. The social contract was essential to the founding of the United States, but the digital age is bringing new changes to this centuries-old concept.
The concept of the social contract goes all the way back to the days of Plato. In his Republic, Plato proposed that a just society functions like a ship, where each person plays their role for the common good of the ship, with politicians making laws to help the citizens and citizens utilizing these laws to generate economic and militaristic output.  Plato explored this idea of duty and morality with the “Ring of Gyges” myth, which examined whether people are naturally just or only act justly because of the fear of punishment. After this thought experiment, Plato concluded that laws and social agreements are necessary to curb selfish behavior and promote societal order. Plato’s ideas were monumental as they laid the groundwork for ideas that impacted many forms of government. One of these ideas was the social contract, which Thomas Hobbes formalized in his 1651 political treatise Leviathan, which attempted to answer the question of what makes a government legitimate.
In Leviathan, Hobbes wrote about what he believed humanity would be like if there was no higher government. He argued that in this “natural” state, there would be no laws or authority to restrain individuals, leading to people acting cruelly and selfishly. Without a higher power to regulate a society, people would act purely out of personal desire, often in conflict with others, resulting in a &amp;ldquo;war of all against all.&amp;rdquo; This was a very extreme stance (and he was called out on it many times by his contemporaries), but Hobbes had a very authoritarian viewpoint on government due to him witnessing the chaos of the English Civil War. According to Hobbes, in order for humanity to go beyond this primitive state of life, humans would need to willingly surrender some freedoms to a “sovereign authority” (a government) in exchange for protection and stability. This was the crucial moment where the social contract was born. This new government, Hobbes believed, should have absolute control over their citizens. From this thought experiment, Hobbes concluded that a legitimate government is one that can protect its citizens from the dangers of the state of nature and uphold the “social contract”.
John Locke wrote a more moderate take of Hobbes’s social contract in his Two Treatises of Government (1689). Locke, along with most enlightenment thinkers of the time, were not big fans of an authoritarian regime. Locke believed that in the state of nature, humans are capable of living in peace and cooperation. However, conflicts can arise, so people form governments to protect their life, liberty, and property from unnecessary conflicts. Unlike Hobbes, who believed that an authoritarian government was necessary to prevent chaos, Locke argued for a government that was restricted by the consent of its citizens (a principle called limited government). Therefore, Locke believed a government’s primary goal was to protect the natural rights of its citizens. This became known as the principle of popular sovereignty. Locke also introduced the idea of rebellion. If a government fails to protect its citizens and ensure their natural rights, the government can and should be overthrown by the people.
The social contract, and more specifically the principle of popular sovereignty, became a founding principle of the United States. The most obvious example of this was the fact that the colonists rebelled against the British government, who had been ignoring the “natural rights” of its colonists overseas. A slogan of the American Revolution was “No taxation without representation”, which directly represented the idea of popular sovereignty and the frustration the colonists felt.
The social contract became even more important as the founding fathers began to construct a new government. Jefferson was deeply influenced by Locke, and directly quoted him with the statement “That all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.” This quote nearly identically matched Locke’s quote about the natural rights of citizens: “Being all equal and independent, no one ought to harm another in his life, health, liberty, or possessions.” From these quotes, you can get the sense that the founding fathers (especially Jefferson) were fans of Locke’s social contract.
This becomes even more apparent after the revolution, as the US Constitution was derived from concepts from the social contract. The preamble literally begins with “We the People,” stating that governmental power comes from the people (citizens) themselves. Locke’s beliefs on limiting government influence also led to the creation of the system of checks and balances, which was designed to prevent any one branch of government from becoming too powerful. The Bill of Rights (the first ten amendments to the U.S. Constitution) also reflects Locke’s ideas about the necessity of a government to protect the natural rights of its citizens, as it protects citizens from each other and the government. As a whole, the founding of the US government largely followed the concepts from the social contract put forward by Locke.
Fast forward to the present day. We’ve entered the digital age, where social media giants like Facebook/Meta, Google, Twitter/X, and Amazon have become influential entities that control vast amounts of data and information. These platforms serve as middlemen for much of our online communication, news consumption, and even economic transactions, giving them incredible power over individuals&amp;rsquo; daily lives and making them quasi-governing bodies. In the digital age, personal data has become a key asset. Social media companies collect mind-boggling amounts of information about users&amp;rsquo; habits, preferences, and even (sometimes illegally) conversations. However, unlike governments that are bound by democratic principles, technology companies create their own rules through Terms of Service agreements. These terms are usually super vague and extremely wordy, which leaves users confused about what they have actually agreed to.
This is the new social contract of the internet: companies provide platforms for connection, information, and entertainment, while users pay with their own personal data. However, unlike a traditional social contract, where governments are accountable to citizens, tech companies are primarily accountable to shareholders. This creates a very dangerous conflict of interest, because there’s no clause in this new “digital” social contract that requires companies in the best interest of the users. As a result, we are witnessing the erosion of Locke’s ideals of a true “social contract” and instead witnessing the rise of a new social contract, one that has far more sinister repercussions for users. In the digital age, companies use surveillance and user data to monetize attention and manipulate user behavior, often without informed consent. Examples include targeted ads, behavioral nudges, and the use of AI-powered algorithms to promote content that increases engagement, even if it’s misleading or harmful. Philosopher Shoshana Zuboff coined the term “surveillance capitalism” to describe this new effect in her 2014 essay “A Digital Declaration”.&lt;br&gt;
One of the most well-documented cases of surveillance capitalism is the Cambridge Analytica Scandal. Cambridge Analytica, a consulting company, used Facebook data to aid in the political campaigns of Donald Trump and Ted Cruz, all without the users knowing what was happening behind the scenes. This scandal revealed how social media data could be silently harvested to influence elections and showed the world how dangerous it was for big tech companies to keep people’s personal data (Cambridge Analytica was also doing a bunch of other shady things at the time, including running psyops for British Intelligence).
However, there’s no need to lose hope just yet. There’s a growing movement to redefine the digital social contract to better protect users’ rights and address the power imbalance between individuals and tech companies. Governments are exploring regulations to help protect users and restore the balance of power. For example, the European Union passed the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) which regulates how Big Tech companies store user information and gives users more power over their own personal data. In addition, the concept of digital citizenship is emerging, which suggests that users should have clearly defined rights in the digital space. This “digital citizenship” mirrors the rights that the US government grants its citizens, therefore making a full circle back to Locke’s idea of the social contract.
In conclusion, the traditional social contract that formed the basis of democratic governments is being eroded and redefined in the digital age. The new social contract includes large tech companies that wield more and more power as we become more dependent on technology. We as a society need to find ways to balance the benefits of technology with the need to protect individual rights. In the immortal words of George Santayana, “Those who cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it.” We need to look back at the ideas set forth by Hobbes and Locke to help define this delicate balance for the betterment of humanity and set the precedent for future generations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hegelian Philosophy and the Modern Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hegel-modern-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hegel-modern-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those who cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it.&amp;rdquo; - George Santayana&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The present can seem like a very unstable and turbulent time. It seems as if the world is splitting itself apart, becoming more polarized and opinionated. However, to understand the direction the world is headed, we need to look back in the past for answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Hegel is notorious for being incredibly difficult to read. His works are often long-winded and use poor english to convey his thoughts. However, his ideas are incredibly important to understand. However, one of his ideas is incredibly important to understand: the dialectic. When broken down, the dialectic is not a very complicated idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Starry Night</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/starry-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 09:10:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/starry-night/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the dawn of human civilization, the night sky has captivated us in a way that no other object has. From the silvery moon rising in the sky to the tiny pinpricks of light we now know as stars and planets, humans have spent countless hours observing and documenting the night sky. The process began as far back as the Babylonians and their written record of the night sky, to the Mesoamerican civilizations who based a large majority of their calendar on the moon, and then the Indian and Arabic civilizations with their massive technological advancements to help observe the night sky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marbury V. Madison: The First Supreme Court Case</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/marbury-v-madison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 04:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/marbury-v-madison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On February 24, 1803, the first and most influential supreme court case of America occurred. This case lives in obscurity to most citizens, but without it, the Supreme Court would not have the power it has today. The issue of the case arose from a seemingly simple dispute. It all began during the Election of 1800. When incumbent president John Adams was voted out of office, he created a scheme to keep his party, the Federalists, in control of one of the branches of the government. Adams promoted many Federalists to become circuit judges and justices of peace. This way, the Federalist party could control the Judicial Branch of the government. However, one man that was promised a commission, William Marbury, never received one before Jefferson came into office. Jefferson declared the commission void and told his Secretary of State, James Madison, to not deliver the commission. Marbury sued Madison, and the court case began. The Supreme Court case Marbury v. Madison changed America for the better because it established the principle of judicial review, increased the power of the Supreme Court, and protected the rights of citizens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China’s History Matters So Much</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-china-history-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 22:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-china-history-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi. It’s been a while. Sorry for not writing at all! I’ve been pretty busy, but I didn’t write because I was very lazy. So anyways, I’m back! Let’s get into today’s topic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China. You can’t read the news without hearing about China. China is predicted to take over the US as the number one global superpower by 2032, and some estimate that to be even earlier. But how did this happen? As always, when you look at a topic, start with the basics. How did China begin, and how did their beginning differ from the US? Let’s dive into the birth of China.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
